FERNANDO SILVA

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

E-mail | GitHub | LinkedIn | MyPortfolio

SUMMARY

Computing engineer with a background in developing efficient software applications in a global market. 5+ years of industry experience, including mentoring junior developers to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline. I can deliver software solutions using Javascript, React/Redux, and Ruby/Rails stacks and I also can learn new programming languages quickly. I have solid experience collaborating effectively in remote teams using pair programming and agile methodology. Currently, I'm looking for job opportunities within the software development industry.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, Postgres

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

Soft Skills: Teamwork, Communication, Leadership.

EXPERIENCE

MICROVERSE Remote
Full-stack Web Developer January, 2022 – Present

AwesomeBooks - Web App prototype of a portfolio for professional projects exhibition. (HTML / CSS / JS)

WebDevWeek - Fictitious Event Web for desktop and mobile environments. (HTML / CSS / JS)

MICROVERSE - Remote - Mentor (Volunteer) -

February, 2022 - Present

• Mentoring junior web developers, and providing technical support through code reviews and advice.

CERVEJARIAS KAISER BRASIL - M. Mirim, SP, Brazil - Software Development Analyst March 1991 - April 1992 (1 year)

- Implemented UML concepts in the System development process.
- Successfully answered all business requirements and redirected them to the appropriate team when needed.
- Proposed new ideas and communicated effectively with the team about updates and project management.

MARSICANO - Salto, SP, Brazil - Software Development Analyst

October 1989 - March, 1991 (2 years)

- Lead the Business Process Redesign for Finance and HR in a 10+ members team for System Development.
- Effectively communicated with C level about the project deliverables and results.

GRUPO CHIARELLI - Salto, SP, Brazil - Applications Development Analyst

April, 1984 – March, 1989 (5 years)

- Evaluated and proposed new technologies to speed-up system development process.
- Created dynamic forms to allow 250+ users to enter, edit, and/or delete transactions.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE - Remote Full-Stack, Web Development Program, Full Time

January, 2022 - Present

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously
 developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React/Redux, Database management with Postgres and MySQL.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily stand-up meetings to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

UNIVESP - Virtual University of São Paulo, SP, BRAZIL (EAD) - BA, Computing Engineering

August, 2018 - Present

FGV FUNDAÇÃO GETÚLIO VARGAS - SP - BRAZIL - MBA, Business and IT Strategic Management

October, 2006